A Guide to the Surveys of the Virginia Land Office before 1779, A-W, 1733-1776
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Surveys of the Virginia Land Office before 1779, A-W, 1733-1776
The Library of Virginia
LOI 4
.45 cu. ft. (1 box)
Virginia. Colonial Land Office.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession LOI 4 transferred by the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1948.
Historical Information
The act which established the previous Land Office next hit passed the General Assembly on 22 June 1779. The register was the head of the Office and was appointed by joint ballot of both houses of the legislature.
Scope and Content
These records contain plats and descriptions returned to the Colonial Land Office prior to 1779. In some instances these surveys were not carried through to a patent; most were either lodged or caveated. Each document gives the name of the individual for whom the survey was made, the county in which the land was located, the number of acres in the tract, its metes and bounds, and the date on which the survey was made. The instrument was signed by the surveyor and includes the names of his chain carriers.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
Surveys of the Virginia Land Office, 1773-1776
Arranged chronologically
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Virginia. Land Office
Subjects:
Surveying -- Virginia -- 18th century.
Genre and Form Terms:
Land surveys -- Virginia -- Albemarle County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Amherst County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Augusta County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Bedford County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Botetourt County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Brunswick County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Buckingham County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Caroline County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Chesterfield County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Dinwiddie County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Fairfax County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Fincastle County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Gloucester County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Goochland County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Halifax County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Hanover County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Isle of Wight County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- James City County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Louisa County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Lunenberg County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Middlesex County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Nansemond County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Norfolk County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Northampton County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Pittsylvania County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Prince George County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Princess Anne County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Rappahannock County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Spotsylvania County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Surry County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- Warwick County.; Land surveys -- Virginia -- York County.; State government records.
Contents List
- Surveys of the Virginia Land Office, 1773-1776., Extent: 1 box.
  Alphabetical.
  - Alexander, Joseph. Augusta County, 21 Feb. 1765. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Allen, John. Goochland County, 25 March 1743. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allen, William. Albemarle County 8 Apr. 1749. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anthony, James. Hanover County, 30 Oct. 1739. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bankinship, Isham. Bedford County, 28 Feb. 1767. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Blayr, William. Augusta County, 29 Jan. 1771. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bowden, Burwell. Pittsylvania County, 29 Oct. 1774. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Briggs, Benjamin. Surry County, 19 Dec. 1748. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Brown, Benejah. Albemarle County, 5 April 1773. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Brown, Israel. Lunenburg County, undated. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Burk, Willim. Augusta County, 14 April 1749., 2 files (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Butler, John. Prince George County, 22 Dec. 1774. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Butler, John. Prince George County, 24 Dec. 1774. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Butler, John. Prince George County, 27 Dec. 1774. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Call, William. Prince George County, 1 May 1775. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Callaway, William. Bedford County, 14 Dec. 1762. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Callaway, William. Bedford County, 17 Dec. 1762. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Carr, Demsey. Nansemond County, 6 June 1771. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Chiswell, John. Albemarle County, 5 Nov. 1755. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Christian, James. Albemarle County, 14 Nov. 1747. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Christian, William. Northampton County, 24 April 1771. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Christian, William. Fincastle County, 12 May 1774. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Claiborne, Augustine. Chesterfield County, 15 Dec. 1772. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Claiborne, Augustine. Chesterfield County, 23 Dec. 1772. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cobbs, Samuel Jr. Albemarle County, undated., 2 files (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Coffy, Edmond. Amherst County, 27 March 1767. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Conaway, Henry. Halifax County, 10 Dec. 1764. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Cornish, William. Lunenburg County, 17 Dec. 1743. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Cornwell, Jacob. Surry County, undated. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Craig, Thomas. Albemarle County, 27 Nov. 1772. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Cunningham, Andrew. Lunenburg County, 13 Dec. 1746. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Currie, George. Lunenburg County, 10 Nov. 1747. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Custard, Paul. Augusta County, 24 Feb. 1773. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Dabney, George. Hanover County, 11 April 1734. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Dance, Stephen. Dinwiddie County, 24 March 1772. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Daniel, Henry. Middlesex County, 14 Sep. 1769. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Davidson, John. Augusta County, 14 Dec. 1769. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Duncle, John. Augusta County, 14 Oct. 1772. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Easley, William. Goochland County, 4 Feb. 1742. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Evans, Stephen. Lunenburg County, 14 Nov. 1748. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - French, James; assignee of William Harris. Bedford County, 28 May 1760. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Fry, Joshua, and John Warren. Albemarle County. 11 Oct. 1749. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Freeman, Charles. Gloucester County, 3 March 1748. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Fulgham, Charles. Isle of Wight County, 13 April 1764. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Ganaway, John. Goochland County, 29 March 1743. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - George, John. Halifax County, 12 April 1756. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Goolsby, Thomas. Albemarle County, 7 May 1772. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Griffin, James. Halifax County, 31 Oct. 1771. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Haile, Mesheek. Bedford County, 8 April 1765. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Hall, John. Prince George County, 31 Dec. 1774. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Haly, William. Prince George County, 21 July 1741. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Harrison, Battile. Amherst County, 4 March 1767. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Harvy, Thomas. Lunenburg County 3 Dec. 1746. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Henderson, Samuel. Bedford County, 16 March 1749. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Hilton, John. Brunswick County, 26 Sep. 1772. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Holland, Michael. Hanover County, 2 Dec. 1736. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Hopkins, Joshua, and John Jones. Norfolk County, 12 Nov. 1772., Oversize. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Hopson, Nicholas. Lunenburg County, 15 Dec. 1749. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Howison, Thomas. Spotsylvania County, 17 Dec. 1743. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Jennings, John. Buckingham County, 25 Sep. 1764. (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Johns, Robert. Albemarle County, 1 March 1747. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Jopling, Ralph. Amherst County, 12 April 1774. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Kannon, William. Lunenburg County, 9 March 1747. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Kavenaugh, Charles. Fincastle County, 29 March 1775. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Lambert, John. Brunswick County, 17 Oct. 1771. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Liverit, Robert. Brunswick County, 11 March 1743. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Liverate, Robert. Lunenburg County, 5 March 1749. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Maclin, William, Duglas Wilkins, and Benjamin Harris. Brunswick County, 3 Feb. 1763. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Madison, John Jr (assignee of Gibbons Jennings). 29 March 1740. (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Matthews, Sampson, and George Matthews (assignee of John Caldwell). Augusta County, 28 Oct. 1772. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Maupin, Daniel. Albemarle County, 7 Nov. 1748. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - McClelan, William. Augusta County. 16 Feb. 1768. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - McDaniell, Michael. Brunswick County, 25 Nov. 1745. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Mead, William (assignee of Francis Sharp and John Boyston). Bedford County, 15 Dec. 1767. (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Mead, William, William Austin, and Isham Talbott. Pittsylvania County, 14 Nov. 1770. (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Mercer, John Jr. Norfolk County, 18 Sep. 1761. (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Miller, Alexander. Augusta County, 29 April 1774. (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Moody, Matthew. York County, 17 May 1773. (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Morris, Hugh. Goochland County, 23 March 1740. (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Morton, Joseph. James City County, 1 April 1760. (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Muir, Robert. Fairfax County, 27 May 1776. (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Napier, Booth. Albemarle County, 23 Oct. 1746. (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Neelly, James. Botetourt County, 10 July 1772. (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Newsum, Lucy. Brunswick County, 31 March 1774. (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Parrish, Alexander. Goochland County, 4 April 1739. (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Pattan, Alexander (assignee of William Miller). Amherst County, 5 March 1746. (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Peartree, John. Augusta County, 3 Nov. 1770. (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Pickett, Maze. Carolina County, 15 Dec. 1750. (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Powell, Seymour Jr (assignee of Seymour Powell). Harwick County, 16 June 1738., Oversize. (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Procter, Joseph (assignee of Nicholas Procter). Brunswick County, 11 Jan. 1754. (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Pruit, Michael. Bedford County, 26 Jan. 1764. (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Ralston, Matthew. Botetourt County, 19 June 1771. (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Randolph, William. Bedford County, 21 Feb. 1754. (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Randolph, William. Halifax County, 29 March 1754. (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Reid, John. Amherst County, 14 Nov. 1769. (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Reid, John. Amherst County, 22 April 1771. (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Rhinhart, Adam. Augusta County, 13 Dec. 1753. (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Riddell, Cornelius. Augusta County, 7 June 1769. (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Rodgers, Andrew. Lunenburg County, undated. (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Ruddell, Cornelius (assignee of Thomas Pickens). Augusta County, 22 June 1768. (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Ruffin, John, and James Baker. Lunenburg County, 19 April 1749. (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Runkle, Peter (assignee of Jacob Runkle). Augusta County, 23 April 1770. (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Scott, James (assignee of Peter Hogg). Augusta County, 26 April 1776. (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Sikes, Henry. Norfolk County, 5 March 1754. (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Simmerman, Christopher. Spotsylvania County, 30 Nov. 1733. (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Smith, James. Chesterfield County, 15 May 1759. (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Smith, John. Bedford County, 4 Nov. 1762. (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Snyder, John Jr. Albemarle County, 16 April 1761. (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Spurlock, Drury. Albemarle County, 5 April 1749. (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Stockton, Richard. Goochland County, 28 April 1741. (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Strean, John. Augusta County, 2 Dec. 1754. (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Taliaferro, Charles. Goochland County, 16 March 1743. (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Trimble, Moses. Botetourt County, 10 Oct. 1772. (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Turner, Joseph. Isle of Wight County, 31 March 1746. (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Walden, Richard. Halifax County, 3 April 1754. (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Walke, Thomas, and John Wildbour. Princess Anne County, 4 June 1748. (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Walton, William (heir of Joseph Walton). Lunenburg County, 22 Nov. 1753. (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Ward, James. Nansemond County, 21 Sep. 1757. (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Watkins, George. Pittsylvania County, 6 May 1772. (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - West, Thomas. Augusta County, 25 Feb. 1773. (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Whitehurst, Simon. Princess Anne County, 25 Sep. 1748., Oversize. (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Whitney, Jeremiah, Richard Taylor, and Thomas Mathews. Buckingham County, 22 June 1768. (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Williams, Henry. Rappahannock County, 19 May 1758. (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Williams, John, and Israel Brown. Lunenburg County, 28 Feb. 1750. (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Willis, John (assignee of John and Mary Coleman, and Isaac and Sarah Read, coheirs of Henry Embry). Halifax County, 15 March 1749. (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Winfrod, Mary (assignee of Thomas Winford). Bedford County, 7 Dec. 1763. (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Winston, Anthony. Hanover County, 12 Sep. 1751. (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Wood, Christopher. Louisa County, 21 March 1771. (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Wood, William Jr. Albemarle County, 22 Oct. 1772. (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Woods, Samuel (assignee of Edward Stephenson). Albemarle County, 10 March 1756. (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Wynne, Samuel. Brunswick County, 21 Dec. 1741. (Box 1, Folder 131)